Stop!
Require assistance!
Assistance required!
Stop where you are!
Stay away from me!
Stop where you are! Stop!
Get off. get off!
Argh! Get off me! Stop!
I told her! No-one listens!
Can you... can you get off me?!
Get off me or you'll die too!
He will not speak
on his own authority!
He will tell you of things to come!
Terrible. terrible things to come!
No! No. no. Dad!
No. no! NO! Dad! No!
No!
Follow my finger.
Two. Three. Four.
Now close your eyes.
What do you see?
Pulling the curtain round the bed.
for privacy.
Can you hear the doctor's voice?
Saying something about...
...nerve damage.
How do you feel?
Like I'm going to throw up.
Because I can't feel my legs.
I can see the nurse.
A sad sympathy face.
I hate it.
- Oh. my God!
- Never seen a mermaid
get out of a pool before?
Inhale.
Two. three. four.
and hold.
Now let's come back.
Three. four and...
...finish.
Take a moment.
Good work today. Gabs. OK?
Yeah. It's hard.
but it helps.
How are you feeling
about your first shift?
Oh...
Work always made me
feel alive. so...
I'm good at what I do.
I want to get that feeling back.
OK. well.
high stress can flare up PTSD.
I know you know that.
Just be aware of the triggers. OK?
Therapist to therapist.
I'm ready.
Good morning!
You're listening
to Radio South Wales.
It's shaping up
to be another scorcher out there.
The mercury is set to break
40 degrees today.
so a reminder to keep hydrated
and stay inside
during the hottest part of the day.
Activist group The Climate Front
are warning temperatures like these
are only likely to continue.
This really is starting to feel like
a never-ending summer.
isn't it. John? I can barely think
straight in this heat.
Hi. it's Dr Gabrielle Fox
for the Child and Adolescent unit.
Is it always so hot in here?
No aircon. Temperatures rise.
but budgets fall.
Oh. um. there's the therapy room.
the rec room...
...and this is your office.
Oh. um. just a little bit
of light reading.
- Oh. great.
- Yeah. if you can
familiarise yourself with that.
There's a staff briefing
in about an hour.
Oh. and. um. Dr Fox.
welcome to Oxsmith.
It's really great
to have you on board.
Thanks.
Let's start with
the highest needs. Yeah?
- Bethany Krall.
- Daughter of Leonard - The Faith Way guy.
Killed her own mother
with a screwdriver in the eye.
Quite chilling.
Fortunately.
child protection prevented
any of the gruesome details
from leaking.
OK. Er. my predecessor's reports
are surprisingly minimal.
Did she leave any additional
notes anywhere?
Not to my knowledge.
Dr Ehmet?
No. Afraid not.
I assume she's under a Section 41?
Yeah. no release without approval
from a tribunal
- or a Ministry of Justice.
- And treatment-wise?
She's on anti-psychotics. mostly.
Sometimes lorazepam for sedation.
- if she's being particularly violent.
- And is she?
Yeah. there have been
a few incidents.
She often needs to be restrained.
We try to make that a last resort.
but she has injured
several members of staff.
Does Leonard Krall visit?
He spends a lot of time
on the road at his churches.
But he does come back here
at least once a month.
and he always makes
a request to see her.
Always refused by Bethany.
Mm. Yes.
Oh. Rafiq is Bethany's
main nurse contact.
He has a good rapport with her
and will usually be present
in her sessions.
What do you make of her. Rafiq?
She's very smart.
OK. so moving on.
Emily Baxter.
Right. agoraphobia
and chronic anxiety.
Emily?
I'm Dr Fox.
You can call me Gabs.
How do you feel about coming
to the therapy room for a session?
Switch off
and pretend we're not doomed.
Is that what YOU do?
Sometimes. yeah.
Simon Keegan -
goes by the name Sonic.
Emotional dysregulation.
complete lack of impulse control.
I see from your notes
that you like puzzles. Sonic.
so I bought this one
in case it helps
to have something to focus on?
Have you met her yet. miss?
It's today. isn't it?
Yes. today.
Wait.
I want to close my eyes.
Bethany. come on. No games.
Right...
You ready?
Hiya.
No. this is wrong.
Are you expecting someone else?
I knew you had a car crash -
I didn't know you were a cripple.
Bethany...
No. it's OK.
I'm your new clinical psychologist.
Dr Fox.
You can call me Gabs.
And I prefer "wheelchair user".
Uh...
You start with five stars.
- Five stars?
- OK...
...you can have six.
Positive discrimination
and all that.
And what are these stars for?
Intelligent psychological practice.
- Mm!
- I'm serious.
I have seen so many of you.
Session one - gain
the patient's trust. Textbook.
If you can do that
without losing your stars...
...I might let you
see me again.
And how can I gain your trust?
By not asking stupid questions.
And what constitutes
a stupid question?
That. You lose a star.
What would you like to talk about?
How about you wearing make-up.
even though no-one's going to look
at you like that ever again?
Thought the last shrink was tragic.
Dr Morgan?
- Mm-hm.
- Your previous psychologist.
Ugh...
You seem angry. Bethany.
Yeah. of course I'm angry.
I'm in prison.
That's a star
for the dumbest question yet.
It's not a prison. it's a hospital.
- Are you afraid of me?
- Bethany...
Are YOU afraid of you?
Ugh!
That's another star. Three left.
Choose your words wisely. Wheels.
Do you like to set the parameters
of all your conversations. Bethany?
Does it make you feel powerful?
Stop flirting with me.
Or perhaps. by making this exchange
a test. it allows you to control it.
How can I help you feel safe?
Two tiny stars left for Dr Wheels.
Are you flirting with ME now?
You been swimming?
Do I smell of chlorine?
No.
Just desperation.
You probably spend every night
on your own.
stalking people
you used to know online.
Bethany.
Your dad's big on the internet.
isn't he?
Are you. um. like. 100 years old?
He's an influencer. yeah.
The "choose hope" guy.
Tell me about him.
Family! That's very original.
That is another star.
And when did you lose trust
in your dad?
When he believed I killed my mum.
And you didn't?
You have my files.
Read them.
Uh...!
And she's out.
Well. then. Thank you.
Rafiq?
- Yes.
- What. that's it?
Giving up already?
You can decide
if you want to see me again.
Hands.
The more depressing
the world feels...
I'm Leonard Krall...
We have 278 affiliated centres
across the UK.
And for those of you
new to religion.
when I talk about God.
I mean a higher power...
But knowing that we're guided
by something greater than ourselves
allows us to have hope.
Yeah. there's one patient.
She seemed to know things about me.
Well. about the crash.
A lucky guess. perhaps?
How did it make you feel?
Angry. actually.
Yeah. Like - that's mine.
don't come near it.
Guess I forgot what it's like
to sit. day in. day out.
with other people's trauma.
I'm fine. It's just a job.
I used to have a pretty good system
for all this.
I'd go for a run.
and if that didn't work.
I'd seduce Alex
and shag the frustration out.
Is that something you miss?
I can't imagine...
Oh. I feel totally cut off
from that part of myself now.
I can't imagine anyone
but Alex ever touching me.
Or if I'd even feel it if they did.
Did you speak to your sister?
She's busy. I'm busy.
And what about the group events
at the spinal unit?
Did you join any?
I couldn't bring myself to.
They all look too... happy.
Yeah. one of them wears
a "Choose Hope" T-shirt.
and that is my litmus test
for twats.
Loneliness is very real. Gabrielle.
Not having a single person nearby
who you can talk to isn't healthy.
I have you.
Hi. All right? Sorry.
you've just really got to jab at it.
Oh!
I'm going back in with Bethany now.
Is it possible
to contact her previous psych.
see if she's got any paper notes?
Er. do you have a number?
Um. Dr Morgan's
had some health problems.
so I'm not sure
that would be appropriate.
- Ah.
- Oh. there you go.
Thanks.
You know it doesn't work inside.
One step at a time. Bethany. hmm?
Hey.
Wheels!
Woo-ooo!
Trying to win me over?
Am I trying to gain
your trust? Yeah.
Do you want draw something for me?
What. and then you analyse
my scribbles?
No.
Well. drawing can be a good way
of bypassing the conscious mind.
Circumventing verbal defences.
Told you.
I've seen a lot of shrinks.
Too many walls.
I get messages from the earth.
I need to be outside
to receive them.
What kind of messages
does the earth send?
Visions...
...of the future.
- So what's coming?
- Terrible...
...terrible things.
Give it a go.
Wow!
Is that how you feel?
Come on!
You can do better than cliches
like that.
A storm is destructive.
Is that maybe how you feel
about yourself?
I didn't kill my mum.
Remember?
In your version of events.
who did?
That's what YOU have to work out.
No. No. that's the role
of the police and the legal team.
My role is to help you make sense
of your actions.
Mm. you're here to find the truth.
And how would I do that?
Get me outside. Wheels.
and we'll see.
- Make sure those names are down for tonight.
- Ed...
- Oh! Yeah.
- I was thinking of taking some
art materials into the garden
for our next session.
She seems to want to draw.
It could help bypass
any verbal defences.
Oh. come on. I'm not going to let
her loose with the Stanley knife.
OK. Don't make me regret it.
Oh. you fancy an Oxsmith
outing tonight?
Some big energy company
is building a wind farm.
They're trying to get
the local community on side.
All the big employees in the area
have been invited.
Ah. no. it's not really my thing.
Schmoozing the locals with booze?
Free booze?
- Gail?
- Yeah?
- Can we make sure that.
uh. Dr Fox's name is on the list
- for the Trenmoor do?
- Yeah. of course.
Choose from a carefully
curated selection
of secluded romantic locations
and activities.
Find your paradise together.
and book online now
to save 40% on family getaways.
Book online now. to save 40%
on family getaways. Discount applies
to selected properties
and departure dates only.
and is available
on new bookings made online
before midnight
on the 30th of September.
Some report increased ability
to achieve orgasm through vibration.
Modified vibrators are available...
...for people with limited mobility.
You're on a journey of exploration.
Get to know your body.
give yourself time and space
to know what you love.
It might be different from before.
but that's OK.
There's no right
or wrong way to orgasm.
There's only your way.
Don't put pressure on yourself.
You're far more likely
to achieve the big O
if you embrace the three Cs -
confidence. curiosity...
...most importantly. connection.
Thanks. Thanks.
Could you move. please? Thank you.
Some of these protesters have got
completely the wrong end
of the stick.
cos we're actually proposing
to build a wind farm.
which is going to provide
100 local jobs
and will boost growth
for the region.
I'm going to hand you over now
to your local MP.
the formidable Caroline Wren.
Diolch yn fawr iawn. Max.
Well. it'll be no surprise
to most of you
that I support Trenmoor Energy's
planning application.
I grew up in Porth Hen.
My dad and his dad worked
in the local steel plant.
and they were proud
to serve the nation.
We can't go back.
but we can go forward.
and welcoming companies
like Trenmoor marks the start
of the regeneration we need.
Uh. red. please.
No. then.
Thank you.
Nice to meet you. too.
Hi. Dick Carwyn. Porth Hen Gazette.
How do you feel about
the new wind farm - for or against?
Oh. I'm just here for the free wine.
I know nothing about all this.
The white is undrinkable.
even for me.
Hey. you work at Oxsmith?
Yeah.
That's where Bethany Krall
is. right?
I can't talk about anyone
at the hospital.
There are laws - as well you know.
I wrote several pieces on
the Kralls. back when I wrote
real articles for a real newspaper.
Condemned to
the Porth Hen Gazette now.
How is that still a thing?
I've got a Substack.
but even less people read that.
and they pay zilch.
Well. check it out.
- Oh. wait.
- Wait. watch it.
Darling. is this man bothering you?
No... my love.
He was just leaving.
Well. you've got my details
if you want to talk.
I know a lot about the Krall family.
- Local hack.
- Yeah. he's... he's been doing the rounds.
He's a nuisance.
So are you part of all this. then?
Yeah. 'Fraid so.
I'm trying to think
of something intelligent to ask.
Oh. thank God. You don't give a shit
about any of this. do you?
I work for the NHS -
can't afford our own booze.
- OK!
- Gabs.
- Oh. Frasier. Hi.
- Hi.
Yeah. my God. I'm done too. I think.
Handshakes. speeches.
photos - check.
- Time to go. I'm starving.
- Yeah. I thought there'd be proper food.
So did I!
Um. I'm actually going for a pizza
if you wanted to join.
Oh. no. thanks.
Pizza might be your code word
for "axe".
Yeah. can't be too careful!
Yeah. thanks for the offer.
but. um...
Sorry if that was. um.
weirdly forward.
I've just. um...
I just moved here recently.
so I don't really know anyone. Um...
But you probably have
actual friends.
Bloody mad!
You know. you know.
pizza sounds great.
- Yeah?
- Mm-hm.
- OK.
Give me that.
Pizza sounds great! This way.
Oh. shit. where did I put that axe?
So. what brings you to Porth Hen?
I take it you're not
from here either.
- Uh. Manchester.
- Mm.
But Cardiff has
a great spinal recovery unit.
so I originally moved
to be near that.
- I had a car accident.
- I'm sorry.
And...
...then I got a job at Oxsmith.
- so I decided to stay.
- OK.
It must be hard being away
from... hometown.
Actually. it's easier this way.
Hard to be around people
with unchanged lives.
It's...
I miss my sister.
But she's on baby number three.
so. you know. busy.
How about you?
Um. I just relocated for this job.
I'm a geologist by trade. but I. um.
I transferred from the London office
to work on the wind farm.
So is it true
what The Climate Front is saying?
And the protesters?
Trenmoor still has a load
of oil sites?
Yeah. they do.
but all UK drilling has stopped.
And. I mean. you can't
just go green globally overnight.
I'm all for activism. but I think
protesting a wind farm event
is maybe a little overzealous.
To be honest.
I mainly switch the news off.
Been more focused on saving myself
than the planet.
Tell me about that.
This isn't a date. you know.
Of course not.
No. I mean. I only date
geological matter anyway.
Sorry!
Ah. thank you.
Hi. Gabs. Uh. dinner tonight?
And I can cook.
if you're still up for it?
Seven? I'll bring the wine.
Having one new green project
in the UK does not make up
for their 76 oil sites
around the world.
Trenmoor's Porth Hen wind farm
is a classic greenwashing exercise.
and they are still lobbying to open
a new oil site in the North Sea.
The Rostyre field was only halted
by a legal case
launched by The Climate Front.
We need to come together to change
the system. not the climate.
Where did you get the pen?
Ugh!
Do you think I'm going to take
your eye out with a Biro?
Didn't get anything new anyway.
I've seen this one before.
It must be close.
What does Jesus mean to you.
coming from a religious background?
Did they actually pay you
to make observations like that?
Something big is coming.
Something that will help me find out
who killed her.
But I can't get it in here.
Please.
We'll start in the courtyard.
If you behave.
we'll progress to the lawn.
Deal?
No restraints?
No restraints.
Look. She's new.
I knew you'd bring
something good.
Who is she?
I have no idea.
Maybe someone you met before?
I don't think so.
She's related to my mum somehow...
...to why she died.
Do you want to tell me about that -
your mum dying?
I saw it before.
I warned her.
And she didn't listen.
She did.
We just didn't know when.
Couldn't see that.
I see the way you're looking at me.
Last psych did the same.
"Poor child.
Can't admit what she did."
Is that how it feels? Hard to admit?
Missing the point.
It's not about my feelings.
It's about the fact
that I didn't kill her.
I would never hurt her.
You know. some patients find it hard
to process their guilt.
They try to find ways
of rationalising their actions.
Do you accept your own actions?
It was your fault. wasn't it?
The accident that put you in that?
I know you're upset. Bethany.
but I'd appreciate it if you didn't
speak about my personal life.
Oh. but it's OK to talk about mine?
This is your therapy session.
and I'm just trying
to understand you.
I don't want your understanding.
I want you to get me out of here.
Did she ever request a legal appeal
against her conviction?
Yes. Um...
She did. right at the start.
The lawyer said
she didn't have no grounds.
but she kept asking Dr Morgan
to try again.
And did she?
What happened to Dr Morgan?
Did Dr Morgan have
a mental health crisis?
If I'm expected to give patients
the best support.
I need to know the full history.
Yes. OK. um. Joy Morgan
had a breakdown.
Bethany got too much for her.
And you didn't think
to disclose that?
I didn't think it was relevant.
She repeatedly
denies responsibility.
Did Bethany ever give her
any new evidence
that might form
the basis of an appeal?
Bethany has had
multiple assessments. Gabrielle.
Now. whether you want
to call it narcissism
or antisocial personality disorder.
she is calculating and deceptive.
She has always claimed
she's innocent.
but she's guilty of murder
and very dangerous.
She needs to be on medication
and in a secure unit.
Yeah. and with the Section 41.
she will be -
for the rest of her life.
She'll transfer to the adult unit
at 18 and probably never get out.
So before I work on getting her
to accept responsibility.
I need to be sure
of what I'm dealing with.
It's not normal protocol.
but given the lack of detail
in the notes.
I need to speak to the lawyer.
Sorry about the lift being
out of order.
I'm on the top floor.
so it's intolerably hot.
Anyway. we're better off down here.
Can I ask you. as a lawyer.
did Bethany ask for an appeal?
Right after the conviction.
I had to advise against.
No new evidence has been
brought since then.
Can you talk me through her case?
You know. seeing as I'm here.
Helpful background.
Bethany had been alone
with her mother that day.
Leonard Krall had spent
the morning in meetings.
When he returned home.
he entered the kitchen.
where he found his wife dead
on the floor.
Coroner's report said she must
have been there at least an hour.
Bethany was sitting next to her.
covered in her blood.
Carys's left eye had been
penetrated with a screwdriver.
and the wound was deep
into her brain.
Right.
Leonard's time of arrival home
was corroborated
by the doorbell camera.
But no-one actually saw it happen?
Correct.
We stressed the lack of witnesses.
but the jury weren't convinced.
The doors and windows
were all locked.
No sign of forced entry.
The only people in the house
were Carys and Bethany.
Did you think she was guilty?
She never confessed.
This might sound like
a weird question.
but were there any
drawings involved?
Yeah. The strangest
and most damning thing of all
was that Bethany had drawn
an image of the crime
about a week before it happened.
It's not strictly professional.
but I think you should see it.
The exact way Carys was murdered.
A grisly threat...
...or. as Bethany claimed.
a premonition of an event
that was yet to happen?
As the UK bakes
under record temperatures.
The Climate Front leader.
Anika Drake.
has claimed. "We are on the brink
of a tipping point."
urging the Government to commit
to banning new fossil fuel projects
such as the Rostyre oil field
in Scotland.
Nice to see you! How are you?
- Welcome.
- Hey.
- We've got designated
seating at the front.
I'm... I'm going to just stay here.
Thank you.
- - We stand united.
- We are not alone.
We trust in a higher power.
We are together in our hope.
Welcome. friends.
to this place of peaceful worship.
And it's nice and cool in here. too.
isn't it?
It's wonderful to be
back home again.
When I travel the country.
we say that prayer is
a collective affirmation.
and we need that.
because modern life feels like
an assault sometimes.
doesn't it?
It's too hot.
We're running out of time.
The planet's dying.
We can't just enjoy the sunshine.
Apparently. we have to fear it.
They want to keep us in a doom loop.
Exhausted. Despairing.
"May the God of hope fill you
with all joy and peace."
is what it says in Romans.
It seems to me we should be
looking on the bright side more.
Look at us humans - we make
families. we do great things.
we find solutions. We wake up
and feel the light of a new day.
just like Christ did
2.000 years ago.
The planet was here then
and the planet is still here today.
Dr Fox?
I looked you up.
I take an interest
in my daughter's care.
Are you here for the service.
or in a professional capacity?
I-I. um...
It's OK. You were curious.
I would be too.
Let's talk.
What did you think of the service?
I didn't expect it to be so...
...climate changey.
Well. the young are
constantly served up doom.
Every generation deserves hope.
don't you think?
No.
God isn't really my thing.
Well. the word is very loaded.
Really. it's just a matter
of semantics.
We all yearn for meaning
in our lives.
Pretty radical for a Christian.
to say God's optional.
Well. think of it as a rebranding.
Thanks. Lulu. Different language
for a very different time.
Same heart.
You probably know
she's refused my visits.
I'm not allowed to discuss
what goes on in sessions.
And yet. here you are.
visiting my church.
Is she studying?
How does she pass the time?
She likes art. as you know.
What's she been drawing?
Bethany has a right
to confidentiality.
They started when she was
about 10 or 11. these visions.
Puberty. I suppose.
Dramatics.
Lots of death and despair.
And did she look for things
to validate them?
Oh. yes.
She saw evidence everywhere.
She took coincidences
and twisted them.
Human mind's a powerful thing.
You know that.
We can convince ourselves
of almost anything.
There was nothing real. of course.
Just extreme mental illness.
Carys was distraught.
She tried everything.
In the end. all we could do
was pray for her.
Did you ever think
she'd hurt anyone?
No. not in my wildest dreams.
and definitely not the person
she loved most in the world.
I miss her.
That may surprise you.
after what she did.
She's my only child.
I don't want to lose her
as well as my wife.
I won't give up on her.
You understand that. don't you?
Hiya.
- You forgot.
- No. I got stuff for both of us.
Um. bleach. Haribo.
and a ready meal.
For one.
Nice to share.
So. uh. what do teenagers
worry about. then?
Oh. all sorts.
One patient fixates
on the infinity of space.
another says she can see
the future. so...
Oh! Expect a stranger
with banging culinary skills
coming into your life
in the weeks ahead.
Nice!
Mm! So good.
- Yeah?
- Mm-hm. I forgot what
real food tastes like.
It's lovely to have someone
who appreciates it.
My ex-wife was not a foodie.
Ex-wife? Do tell.
Oh! Shuffles in his seat. reticent.
Oh. my God. please don't do that.
OK. No. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Go on.
Oh. I don't know. I mean.
she just hated my job. really.
And even when I transferred
to Renewables. it wasn't enough.
because I was still working
for a company that invested in oil.
But. I mean. I don't think anything
was ever going to be enough.
And I guess that just made it
impossible to be together.
Ethical differences.
- Very modern.
- Oh. thank you very much.
How about you?
- Um...
- Shuffles in her seat. reticent...
- Oh. God!
- No. you really don't have to.
No. um...
I was married...
...but my husband died
in the accident.
Fuck.
Let's... Let's not talk about it.
A severe electrical storm
in Lisbon
caused dramatic damage
to Santuario do Cristo-Rei.
the 90-foot tall statue
of Jesus Christ
that overlooks the city.
The storm devastated areas
of southern Lisbon.
with multiple districts evacuated.
Climate scientists are warning
that these sorts
of extreme weather events
will become increasingly common
across southern Europe
as sea temperatures rise.
Look. Emily. look!
- Look!
- Make him go away!
I-I was delivering the news!
He's goading me!
It's going on in Lisbon.
I heard Blanchett talking!
- OK. that's enough.
- I thought you'd want to know!
I told you! Bethany sees things!
You said we could go
on the back lawn if I was good.
and I was good as fucking gold.
wasn't I? Wheels?
It's 40 degrees.
No-one is going outside today.
Ugh!
Sonic told me about the storm.
You know. the Jesus statue.
Don't you get it now?
Ah! No. You're going to say
it's just a coincidence.
- It could be.
- What a nice. comforting thought.
You need to talk to this woman.
I need to talk to her?
Find her. She's somewhere... remote.
Near water. maybe?
And there's a cat.
She has a feral cat.
Whoever she is.
this woman knows something.
Something about why my mum died.
Bethany. I spoke to your lawyer.
because I needed
to get some clarity.
You spoke to Duval?
But there's no grounds
for an appeal.
There's no new evidence.
There is! This woman has it.
- Look...
- Look!
- Bethany.
- You are wasting too much time. - Bethany.
- You need to find her.
- Let go.
I said let go!
- Heya.
- Sorry about that.
Um. I wasn't quick enough.
No. it's fine. it's fine. Sit down.
What do you make of the storm?
I was wondering how that drawing
would actually come true.
Well. the news has been banging on
about extreme weather for months.
Maybe she picked up on that.
made a guess.
She's seen other things. too.
About you.
So. what did the staff know
about me before I got here. then?
Did it get around that I. er...
...that I'd had an accident?
Yes.
People talk.
Yeah. she used it to spook me.
Like she had seen it.
It's a game.
Her visions come true.
time and time again.
You'll see.
Are you religious?
Er. I am. but not
social media spiritualism.
I'm more agnostic myself.
I struggle with the idea
of prophecy. and...
Yeah.
This is Dr Morgan's phone number.
No-one can know I gave you this.
Talk to her. She'll explain.
Thank you.
Sorry I couldn't meet at the house.
My husband can't know
I'm talking to you.
I promised I'd try to move on.
It's about her. isn't it?
Bethany Krall. yeah.
I need to ask you some questions.
I knew you'd turn up
sooner or later.
It's uncanny.
The likeness.
She knew you were coming.
Bethany would draw things
and they'd happen.
Disasters.
pictures of collapsed buildings.
And the next day on the news.
I'd see it.
It happened all the time.
She wanted to break me.
She did break me.
I needed to leave...
...to make way for you.
She believed her powers
could help her find out
what happened to her mother.
And everything led to you.
She believed you would find
the truth.
I know how freaked out you are.
It's OK.
I've been there.
Well. how...
...how is this even possible?
She just seemed to know things
before they happened.
I tried to figure out
how she was doing it.
She didn't have access to any media.
I mean. the other patients...
Well. people do talk.
staff and patients.
Yeah. but she did this drawing
last winter!
She can see the future.
She has to be able to.
Do you recognise her?
You're meant to find her?
Is that it?
Bethany said this woman knows
something about her mum's death.
Well. then. whoever she is. I...
...I fear for her.
Hello?
Dick Carwyn?
It's Dr Gabrielle Fox.
We met at that wind farm
event thing.
I'm in the Forge Tavern.
Booze ain't free. but it's cheap.
I'll be here all night.
If I had any sense.
I'd let this lie.
The Kralls have already ruined
my life.
But people should know.
You think people should know what?
I wrote a lot about
The Faith Way early on.
It was mad how quickly they got big.
And when Carys Krall was in London
for some school mental health thing.
I interviewed her.
Mm. What was she like?
Genuinely cared about the kids.
I mean. I didn't go in
for the whole.
you know. God stuff. but. er.
she seemed like a good person.
Where's this going?
Skip forward five years.
and she contacts me out of the blue.
They had a huge following by then.
I mean. literally put faith
back on the map.
And because of that.
they'd stopped engaging
with mainstream press -
they didn't need it.
What did she want?
I... don't know.
She said she had
something to show me.
Asked if she could meet me.
I said. "Yeah. of course."
But then she bailed on me
last minute.
Left a voicemail
saying she couldn't come.
Said she was being followed
and she was scared.
Two days later. she was dead.
The elements will melt
with fervent heat.
Both the earth and the works
that are in it will be burnt up.
We're all looking for meaning.
and it's hard. isn't it.
to know how to find purpose
in the modern world
when there's so much choice.
so much information to navigate?
But if we look to a higher power.
we don't have to seek.
We will be found.
What do you think she wanted?
I don't know. I wish I did.
But put it this way -
I don't for one second believe
she wanted to tell me
she was scared of her daughter.
- You don't?
- No. Why would she come to me?
The elements will melt
with fervent heat...
She would have called someone
to section her. or the police. or...
Well. so what. then?
I covered the case.
kept digging around The Faith Way
until I got called in by my editor.
He tells me the lawyers say
it's a no-go.
Reporting restrictions
because Bethany's a minor.
Fair enough. right?
But then I get dismissed.
Suddenly. no national paper
wants me.
and I'm back in Porth Hen.
having to beg for a job
with the bloody Gazette.
Oh. do you still have the voicemail
from her? Can I hear it?
That's the really weird thing -
my phone stopped working.
All my backups were gone.
It wasn't there.
What. and you think that...?
I KNOW someone wanted
that evidence destroyed.
Let us say a collective
prayer of gratitude
to that higher power
for showing us the way.
for finding our lost souls
and guiding us.
Did you call the police?
Of course. But it was
only my word...
Hey! Let's go outside
and see what's happening.
It's some sort of national warning.
Can everyone please calm down?
I'm sure it's OK.
- Calm down.
- Calm down!
- Help! - Calm down. everyone.
- Please. help!
- Help me! - Are we going to die?
- It's probably just a test.
Stop! Stop! Stop. stop. stop. stop!
- Get out of the way!
- Hey! Watch it. mate.
We're together. and there is nowhere
safer than here.
under this roof.
Join with me.
We stand united.
We are not alone.
We trust in a higher power.
We are together in our hope.
This is The Climate Front.
There is no disaster coming tonight.
but there will be
if we don't act now.
It's time to stop the 1%
putting their own greed
before the needs of the 99%.
Join us for the people's strike
this Thursday.
Don't go to work or school.
Take to the streets to demand people
and the planet before profit.
Together we have the power to change
the system. not the climate.
It's coming.
It's a hoax.
- It's coming.
- We're safe.
We're not safe.
What is coming?
The final link in the chain.
The end.
The Rapture.